<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.github.ignaciotcrespo.colormanipulation</id>
    <name>Color Manipulation</name>
    <vendor email="itcrespo@gmail.com" url="https://github.com/ignaciotcrespo">Ivan Crespo</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
    <p>A powerful color toolkit for developers. Select any color in your code, right-click, and convert, adjust, mix, or analyze it — all without leaving the editor.</p>

    <p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ignaciotcrespo/color-manipulation-plugin/main/docs/img/screenshot.png" alt="Color Manipulation Plugin" width="600"/></p>

    <h3>Convert Format</h3>
    <p>Convert between <b>30+ color formats</b> across all major platforms:</p>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Web/CSS</b>: #RGB, #RRGGBB, #RRGGBBAA, #AARRGGBB, rgb(), rgba(), hsl(), hsla(), hwb(), Named CSS Colors</li>
        <li><b>Android/Kotlin</b>: 0xRRGGBB, Color(0xAARRGGBB), Color.rgb(), Color.argb()</li>
        <li><b>iOS/Swift</b>: UIColor(red:green:blue:alpha:), Color(red:green:blue:)</li>
        <li><b>Java</b>: new Color(r, g, b), new Color(r, g, b, a)</li>
        <li><b>Generic</b>: Float RGB/RGBA (0.0-1.0), with and without parentheses</li>
        <li><b>Toggle</b>: Toggle # prefix, Toggle 0x prefix, Swap RRGGBBAA/AARRGGBB byte order</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Convert from Name</h3>
    <p>Convert named colors from popular design systems to hex values:</p>
    <ul>
        <li>CSS Named Colors (red, cornflowerblue, ...)</li>
        <li>Tailwind CSS (gray-800, blue-500, ...)</li>
        <li>Bootstrap (primary, danger, blue-400, ...)</li>
        <li>Material Design (Blue 500, Red 300, ...)</li>
        <li>iOS System Colors (systemBlue, systemRed, ...)</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Adjustments</h3>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Lighten/Darken</b> by preset (5%, 10%, 20%) or custom percentage</li>
        <li><b>Saturate/Desaturate</b> with presets, grayscale, or custom</li>
        <li><b>Adjust Alpha</b>: 100%, 75%, 50%, 25%, 0%, or custom</li>
        <li><b>Hue Rotate</b>: +30, +60, +90, +180 degrees, invert, or custom</li>
        <li><b>Temperature</b>: Warmer/Cooler with presets or custom</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Mixing &amp; Palette</h3>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Color Mixing</b>: Tint (mix with white), Shade (mix with black), custom percentages</li>
        <li><b>Palette Generate</b>: Complementary, Analogous, Triadic, Shades (100-900)</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Accessibility</h3>
    <ul>
        <li><b>WCAG Contrast Check</b>: Shows contrast ratio against white/black with AA/AAA pass/fail</li>
        <li><b>Auto-fix</b>: Make AA or AAA compliant on white or black backgrounds</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Color Blindness Simulation</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>Protanopia (red-blind), Deuteranopia (green-blind), Tritanopia (blue-blind)</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Closest Match</h3>
    <p>Find the closest color in popular design systems and convert to name or value:</p>
    <ul>
        <li>Named CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material Design, iOS System Colors</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Practical Utils</h3>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Random Color</b></li>
        <li><b>Sort Lines</b> by Hue, Lightness, or Saturation (reorders full lines by their color)</li>
        <li><b>Sort Colors</b> by Hue, Lightness, or Saturation (swaps color values in place)</li>
        <li><b>Normalize to Same Format</b>: Convert all selected colors to match the first one's format</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Show Color Info</h3>
    <p>Popup showing all format conversions, HSL values, alpha, and closest matches across all design systems.</p>

    <h3>Replace with Color</h3>
    <p>Replace one or many colors with a custom color value. Type any color format (hex, rgb, hsl, named CSS, etc.) in the dialog and all selected occurrences are updated, each keeping its original format. Available in both the editor menu and the palette context menu.</p>

    <h3>Project Color Palette</h3>
    <p>A dedicated <b>side panel</b> (Tool Window) that scans your entire project and gives you a bird's-eye view of every color in your codebase.</p>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Full project scan</b>: Finds all color occurrences across 40+ file types (CSS, HTML, JS, TS, Kotlin, Swift, Java, Python, Go, Rust, and more)</li>
        <li><b>Tree view</b> organized by frequency or hue, with color swatches and occurrence counts</li>
        <li><b>Similar colors detection</b>: Groups visually similar colors that could be unified into one</li>
        <li><b>Format inconsistencies</b>: Highlights the same color written in different formats across files</li>
        <li><b>WCAG contrast badges</b>: Inline AA/AAA/Fail indicators on every color node</li>
        <li><b>Rich tooltips on hover</b>: Full color details with all format conversions and WCAG contrast ratios</li>
        <li><b>Color Info popup</b>: All formats, HSL, alpha, WCAG contrast with colored pass/fail badges, suggested AA fix with visual swatch preview, and closest matches in CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material, and iOS</li>
        <li><b>Click-to-navigate</b>: Click any occurrence to jump to the exact line and column in the editor</li>
        <li><b>Right-click context menu</b>: Apply the same transforms as the editor menu (convert format, lighten/darken, saturate, hue rotate, mix, accessibility fixes, color blindness simulation) on single colors, multiple selections, or entire groups</li>
        <li><b>Replace with Color</b>: Batch-replace selected colors or groups with a custom color value</li>
        <li><b>Display format selector</b>: View colors in #RRGGBB, rgb(), hsl(), 0x, Color(), or UIColor()</li>
        <li><b>File filter</b>: Narrow the scan to specific file patterns (e.g. *.tsx, *.css)</li>
        <li><b>State preservation</b>: Expanded nodes, selection, and scroll position are preserved across re-scans</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Open it from: <b>View &gt; Tool Windows &gt; Color Palette</b>, or from the right sidebar.</p>

    <h3>More Features</h3>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Repeat Last Action</b>: Quickly re-apply any previous transform (including custom values)</li>
        <li><b>Multi-cursor support</b>: Apply transforms to all selected colors at once</li>
        <li><b>Embedded color detection</b>: Select a block of text and the plugin finds and transforms all colors inside</li>
        <li><b>Live preview icons</b>: See the resulting color in the menu before clicking</li>
        <li><b>Keyboard shortcut</b>: Ctrl+Alt+C (Cmd+Alt+C on Mac)</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Works in <b>all JetBrains IDEs</b> (IntelliJ, WebStorm, Android Studio, PyCharm, etc.) with <b>all file types</b>.</p>

    <br/>
    <p>If you find this plugin useful, consider <a href="https://github.com/sponsors/ignaciotcrespo">sponsoring its development</a>. Your support helps keep it free and actively maintained. Thank you!</p>
    ]]></description>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow id="Color Palette"
                    anchor="right"
                    factoryClass="com.github.ignaciotcrespo.colormanipulation.palette.ColorPaletteToolWindowFactory"
                    icon="/META-INF/colorWheelIcon.svg"
                    secondary="true"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <group id="ColorManipulation.MainGroup"
               class="com.github.ignaciotcrespo.colormanipulation.actions.ColorManipulationGroup"
               text="Color Manipulation"
               description="Color manipulation actions"
               popup="true">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </group>

        <action id="ColorManipulation.QuickAction"
                class="com.github.ignaciotcrespo.colormanipulation.actions.ColorManipulationGroup"
                text="Color Manipulation..."
                description="Open color manipulation popup">
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl alt C"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
